FULL STACK DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Project-focused Full Stack Web Developer with significant experience in the client and server side of applications, as well as collaborating with developers to create intuitive web applications. Specializes in JavaScript, with a focus on MERN stack and MySQL. Professional strengths include creative problem-solving, written and verbal communication, and time management. Strong interpersonal skills from 5+ years of experience in leadership roles.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

LANGUAGES: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, SQL

FRAMEWORKS, LIBRARIES & DATABASES: React, Express, Bootstrap, jQuery, Node, Handlebars, Bulma, Redux, MySQL, MongoDB, GraphQL

TOOLS: Git, Web API, Third-Party API, RESTful API, Sequelize, Mongoose, Webpack, Babel, npm, Figma, Jest, Heroku

PRINCIPLES: Separation of Concerns, Keep it Simple, Don't Repeat Yourself, Refactoring, Documentation, Clean Code, Agile, SCRUM, Mobile First Design, Test Driven Deployment

PARADIGMS & ARCHITECTURES: Object Oriented Programming, Model View Controller, Functional Programming, Object Relational Mapping

PROJECTS

InnerPattern (group) | Deployed Project: http://innerpattern.herokuapp.com/ | Github: https://github.com/Tyl3r-s/InnerPattern

- Mental health focused application where users are able to log in and create, read, update, and delete journal entries which are tied to their account.
- Facilitated communication and organization. Set and tracked team goals. Wireframed initial idea, wrote front end and back end logic, created various components, applied style, and fixed bugs.
- MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Apollo, GraphQL, JTW, bcrypt

Weather App | Deployed: https://tyl3r-s.github.io/weatherapp/ | Github: https://github.com/Tyl3r-s/weatherapp

- Users are able to search for any city around the world and view current weather, including a 5 day forecast.
- Connected to API end points and used jQuery to create a simple series of methods to produce a clear workflow.
- jQuery, HTML, CSS, open weather API.

Tech Bits | Deployed: https://stark-wildwood-39109.herokuapp.com/ | Github: https://github.com/Tyl3r-s/tech-blog

- A CMS-style tech blog site where users are able to create an account and perform all CRUD operations on user posts.
- Connected to MySQL database via Sequelize. Rendered HTML through handbars.js, and used express session to handle log in status.
- Javascript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Sequelize, Express-session, Handlebars

EXPERIENCE

Manager

Oil Changers | Oshawa, ON | October 2021 to July 2022

Oversaw and directed garage resource and workforce issues for the organization. Monitored financial performance to ensure the garage was meeting or exceeding budgetary commitment.

- Eliminated knowledge gaps by managing continuous training and mentoring strategies for new and junior personnel.
- Cut out unnecessary spending and increased efficiency by reorganizing storage and reprioritizing inventory.
- Creatively solved customer issues and provided resolutions to achieve the highest level of customer satisfaction.

Tire and Lube Technician

Oil Changers | Oshawa, ON | January 2021 - October 2021

Prepared detailed vehicle service reports, replaced vehicle wiper blades, filters, and car batteries, changed motor oil as well as transmission and brake fluid as needed, and installed, balanced, and repaired tires for passenger cars and commercial vehicles.

Key Accomplishments:

• Developed good relationships with customers for repeat business.

Lawn Maintenance (self-employed)

Durham Lawn Co | Durham Region, ON, CA | April 2020 - September 2020

Performed multiple landscaping tasks including planting, watering, mulching and edging. Used shears, pruners and chainsaws to prune and trim hedges and shrubs.

Key Accomplishments:

• Performed quality work, building client base via reliable, friendly reputation.

Team Leader | Utility Relief | Assembly Line Worker

General Motors | Oshawa, ON | October 2015 - January 2020

Trained team members and resolved conflicts pertaining to team members, resources, or malfunctions. Stepped into roles as needed. Assembled parts or units, and positioned, aligned, and fastened units to assemblies, subassemblies, or frames, using a hoist, hand tools, or power tools.

Key Accomplishments:

- Displayed creative, on the spot thinking to resolve conflict, not allowing productivity to fall.
- Learned roles swiftly to ensure team integrity.

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate | University of Toronto | May - October 2022

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Git, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Heroku, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Grade: 100.8%